Curriculum Vitae

Daniel Goble

PERSONAL PROFILE

danielgoble@gmail.com danielgoble.com 07889 558 385

I have extensive experience within the creative design industry having worked across a broad range of projects within the fields of user experience and interaction design, user interface design, visual communication and graphic design.

Throughout my career I have applied these disciplines across web based products and services, mobile apps, printed media and television UI.

CAREER HISTORY

YouView TV | July 2015 - Present Interaction Designer

I am currently positioned within YouView as an interaction designer. My primary role here involves helping to create and improve an entirely new user interface for the YouView set top box, allowing users to enjoy a combination of live and on-demand television in a seamless and intuitive manner. Secondary to this, conceptual work on the YouView mobile app is also undertaken. Both projects involve an agile collaboration between UX, visual design and development teams, with projects going through stages of concepting, prototyping and user testing.

T3 Awards 2017 Best TV Platform

The Connies 2017 Winner Contribution to User Experience & Best TV / Video Launch

TV Connect Awards Shortlisted for Best Cloud Based

Video Service & People's Choice

Tandem Bank | June 2015 - July 2015 Digital Designer

Joining this disruptive banking startup, my role involved hybrid UX/UI duties. Primary focus was placed on the conceptualisation and design, both UX and visual, for a series of financial services mobile apps aimed at simplifying common customer needs.

Content Innovation Awards 2017 Winner for Advanced TV Innovation of the Year

Blinkbox Music / WE7 | November 2012 - June 2015 User Experience & Interface Designer

Initially employed as a dedicated user experience designer for the Blinkbox music (formerly WE7) tailored music streaming service, my experience in UI design was latter brought into play as my role evolved into a hybrid UX/UI position.

As part of the UX team I was tasked with creating and enhancing a new online experience, helping to define how users interacted with the UI on both the web and the iOS and Android apps.

Work was carried out in an agile environment and involved a process of sketch sessions, low fidelity prototyping and user testing before any UI design work was then undertaken.

BT Innovation Awards 2008 Finalist for BT Touch

"Thank you for the wonderful Turner On-Line feature.

I live in the US, and this is a fantastic way to share your collection

with those of us unable to visit the gallery in person"

(Tate Online user)

BT Conferencing | April 2009 - September 2012 Senior Creative Designer

Between 2009 and 2012 I was a member of the marketing creative team, within BT Conferencing, providing UX and visual design.

This position presented more opportunity to work on some high profile user/web interface, and site design projects. The role also called upon my HTML/CSS skills.

Highlights include the BT Conferencing website re-design, WebJoin 2.0 and the London 2012 marketing website, as well as many various customer targeted print, web and email campaigns.

BT Design & Usability Group | January 2005 - April 2009 Visual Communication Designer

Moving into the BT Design Group (which later became know as the Usability Group) enabled me to hone my usability and interaction design skills.

Working as part of the leading Usability and Accessibility team within the company - much more focus was placed on a user centred design approach, which I believe has had a hugely positive effect on my work.

Highlights here would include the 2006 Digital Music Awards. This involved the design, and delivery of everything from the main DMA06 website, event tickets, and event stage backdrops, which were covered on Channel 4.

Touch Team (visual branding) Visual/Graphic Designer

Forming part of my time within the Usability Group - I was assigned to 'Project Touch'. This involved the creation and development of a whole visual language specifically for user interface and web based application design.

Working alongside creative agencies - I played a key role in creating, evolving, and applying the new style guide, and integrating this into the BT brand.

BT Openworld & Retail | November 2000 - January 2005 Graphic Designer

I first joined BT as part of the BT Openworld content studio, before moving into BT Retail, I became the lead designer for various projects. The most significant of which was the BT Broadband marketing website, which involved a complete re-design and re-brand.

The highlight from my time here include my work with the Tate Britain gallery, for whom I created the Interactive Turners Gallery - which was heavily covered by the press, and still draws many visitors to the main Tate website. I was also involved in the London 2012 Olympic bid campaign, tasked with the creation of a range of online Olympic marketing material.

Deevaserve Ltd | September 1997 - November 2000 Lead Graphic Designer

The first step in my design career took place in this small agency specialising in internet access and email accounts, for both consumers and small businesses.

CORE SKILLS & EXPERIENCE

User experience and interaction design
User interface design
Visual design for native apps, web and print
User centred design techniques and application
Prototyping (both low and high fidelity)
User research
Information architecture
Usability and basic accessibility principles
HTML, CSS & Basic Coffeescript

FORMAL TRAINING & EDUCATION

User Centred Design (Flow Interactive)
Inclusive Design (best practice)
Framer & Coffeescript
HTML
CSS
Design for Print
Presentation Skills
Typography

National Diploma in Media and Film City & Guilds in motion photography

SOFTWARE PROFICIENCY

I am proficient with most industry standard design and wireframing software. My favourites include:

Sketch App Axure Framer Adobe Photoshop Adobe Illustrator Adobe InDesign

Use of Colour